Hi everyone, I'm very pleased
to welcome you in this course.
You will learn everything
on the LoRaWAN protocol.
We'll do our best to clearly explain
the data transmission between
a LoRaWAN device and a user dashboard.
With the videos, you will also get a free
ebook with all the chapters of the course.
Right now you can check out our Website
to download it for free, as well as
many other tools and documentations.
All this material is available thanks
to our commitment to the Lora Alliance.
Our University and all instructors
are institutional members.
Let's see what you're going
to learn during this training.
You will first learn the basics of the
Lora modulation between two end-devices.
Then between the device and a gateway.
We will explain the LoRa parameters like
the bandwidth, channels
and Spreading Factor.
Then you will learn how to configure
a gateway, and to connect it
to the LoRaWAN Network Server.
At the beginning,
we will first use a community network
to register your gateways,
your applications, and your end-devices.
With this Network Server you will see many
demonstrations with different activation
modes, with different end-device
classes and different frame types.
We'll dive into the LoRaWAN protocol
to explain clearly everything.
Once you will master all the basic
knowledge of the LoRaWAN protocol,
we will create our own private network
with our Network Server
and own Application Server.
You will try two of them which are
ChirpStack and The Things Stack open
source and on this servers
you will build everything.
Finally, you will create your own
IoT Platform and we'll teach you how
to use simple tools to save your data
in a database and to display
them on the dashboard.
At the end of this course,
you should be able to create a complete
IoT solution based
on the LoRaWAN protocol.
Once again,
thank you for choosing this course and let
us know if you have any questions.
We will do our best to answer them.